[{"question":"<p><strong>Climate is the :<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Prevailing weather conditions of a region for 15 years","Prevailing weather conditions of a region for 20 years","Prevailing weather of a region of 30 years","Prevailing weather conditions of a region for 35 years"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"Select year"},{"question":"<p><strong>Igneous rocks are rocks formed by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The cooling of molten minerals  from a liquid into a solid.","The heating of minerals from a solid into a liquid","The deposition of minerals from a solid into liquid","The deposition of  minerals."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"Select year"},{"question":"<p><strong>Temperature is a measure of :<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The average hotness","The average coolness.","The average heat","The average reflection"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"Select year"},{"question":"<p><strong>Isothern refers to:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Line that connects points of  equal sunshine","Line that connects points of equal humidity.","Line that connects points of equal pressure.","Line that connects points of equal temperature"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The longest river in Africa is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["River Zaire","River Nile","River","Niger"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Isobar refers to:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Line that connects points of equal sunshine","Line that connects points of equal humidity.","Line that connects points of equal rainfall.","Line that connects points of equal pressure"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Topographic maps are:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Representations of features on the Earth's surface.","Features on the Earth's surface.","Detailed and accurate graphic representations of features on the Earth's surface","Geographic coordinate grid on the Earth's surface."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Lesotho is in:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Central Africa","East Africa.","West Africa","South Africa."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Weathering of rocks is:&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The building of rocks.","The formations of rocks.","The deformations of rocks.","The breaking down of rocks."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Scale of a map is defined as:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The ratio of a distance on the drawing board to the corresponding distance on the ground","The ratio of a distance on the map to the corresponding distance on the ground.","The ratio of a distance on the tape to the corresponding distance on the ground","The ratio of a distance on the ruler to the corresponding distance on the ground."],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The capital of Niger state in Nigeria is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Minna.","Yola.","Makurdi.","Gusau."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A valley is a:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Highland between hills.","Lowland between trees.","Highland between trees.","Lowland between hills."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria has a total land area of:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["723,768 km2","823,768 km2","923,768 km2","623,768 km2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A lake is a:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Large body of water surrounded by land.","Large body of water surrounded by forest.","Large body of water surrounded by rocks.","Large body of water surrounded by water."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An island is a:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Piece of land surrounded by land.","Piece of land surrounded by forest.","Piece of land surrounded by rocks.","Piece of land surrounded by water."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The ethnic groups in Nigeria are:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["More than 250","More than 150","More than 200","More than 100"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Orographic rainfall is a:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Temperate rainfall.","Coastal rainfall.","Island rainfall.","Relief rainfall."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One major societal issues in Nigeria is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Poor feeding.","Poor human rights.","Poor language.","Poor music."],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The United Nations estimate of Nigeria population in 2009 was:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["144,729,000.","154,325,000.","164,729,000.","174,729,000."],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nigeria lies between:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Latitudes 4\u00b0 and 13\u00b0N and longitudes 2\u00b0 and 15\u00b0E.","Latitudes 4\u00b0 and 14\u00b0N and longitudes 2\u00b0 and 14\u00b0E.","Latitudes 5\u00b0 and 14\u00b0N and longitu es 4\u00b0 and 15\u00b0E.","Latitudes 4\u00b0 and 14\u00b0N and longitudes 2\u00b0 and 15\u00b0E."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Kinshasa is a:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["North African City","West African City","South African City","Central African City"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Freetown is a:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["North African City","West African City","South African City","East African City"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which one of the following countries is having the highest quality of life?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sweden","Austria","United States of America","England"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nairobi is in:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["North African City","West African City","South African City","East African City"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The most populated country in the world is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["China","Austria","United States of America","England"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Casablanca is a:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["North African City","West African City","South African City","East African City"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The World largest Ocean is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Pacific Ocean","Atlantic Ocean","Indian Ocean","Arctic Ocean"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Dominican Republic is in:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Europe","Africa","America","Asia"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The World Longest Coastlines is in:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Canada","Austria","United States of America","England"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A lines drawn on a maps to show places of equal rainfall is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rainline","Isotope","Isotherm","Hydrotope"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Wind erosion is most common in<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rocky areas","Riverine areas","Arid areas","Humid areas"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The act of graphical representation of places with identified scale and legend is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Scaling","Mapping","Sketching","Drawing"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A piece of land almost surrounded by water is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Headland","Isthmus","Island","Peninsula"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Planet warming the use of water transport is limited by all the following except<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Wide valleys","Waterfalls","Seasonality","Narrow gorges"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>To obtain the climate of a place the average atmospheric weather conditions should be considered for<\/strong><\/p>","options":["20years","24years","35years","10years"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is a major hindrance to H.E.P.&nbsp; generation in Africa?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Inadequate capital","Unavailability of good sites","Absence of domestic market","Sufficient volume of water"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Isotherms are lines drawn on maps joining places having equal&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Water level","Pressure","Rainfall","Temperature"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The type of coal found in Nigeria is the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bituminous grade","Sub-bituminous grade","Mini-bituminous grade","High \u2013 bituminous grade"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Precipitation include all the following except<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fog","Snow","Dew","Dust"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The location of iron and steel industry at Ajaokuta in Nigeria is best explained by the presence of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Limestone and coal","River port","Iron ore","Bauxite"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Settlements can be classified according to all the following except the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The arrangements of the building","Number of people per settlements","Main occupation of the inhabitants","The type of people that live in the area"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The average hurricane exists, on the average, for about ________.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Two weeks","Four weeks","Three weeks","One week"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>&nbsp;Refers to the nature of the surface of an area and the features that abound therein above the sea level.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Plain","Hill","Plateaux","Relief"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Any buoyant parcel of air is said to exhibit __________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The dry adiabatic lapse rate","Advection","The moist adiabatic lapse rate","Instability"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The north east and south east trade winds meet along a plane surface where they continuously rub against each other. This surface is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Abnormal front","Lee  ard front","Intertropical front","Wind  ward front"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Is the time of day when tornadoes are most likely to occur.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mid-afternoon","Dawn","Noon","Evening"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Crude oil is ___________ rock mineral<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A sedimentary","An igneous","A metamorphic","A plutonic"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The new name of Calicut, a famous city of Kerala is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Kozhikode","Trivendrum","Kalighat","Koderma"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"}]